Guide to the Julio Elizalde Papers [Guía a los escritos de Julio Elizalde], 1973-2007 LATINAMER.2013.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Writings, 1972-2007; I.
  - Writings, March-June 2002 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Una meditación política: Misión universal del Poder Militar americano [A Political Contemplation: Universal Mission of the American Military Power], 15 de marzo, 2002 [March 15, 2002]; 11.; 4 pages
    - Meditaciones teóricas: El destino de la civilización americana [Theoretical Reflections: The Destiny of the American Civilization], 16 de marzo, 2002 [March 16, 2002]; 12.; 4 pages
    - Un mensaje al F.B.I.: Julio no puede continuar la lucha, optando por retirarse a causa de razones económicas [A Message to the F.B.I.: Julio Cannot Continue the Fight, Opting to Retire Due to Economic Reasons], 18 de marzo, 2002 [March 18, 2002]; 13.; 8 pages
    - Segundo mensaje al Buró Federal de Investigaciones (F.B.I.) (Dividido en incisos) [Second Message to the Federal Bureau of Investigations (F.B.I.) (Divided in Sections)], 19 de marzo, 2002 [March 19, 2002]; 14.; 4 pages
    - Tercer mensaje al F.B.I. [Third Message to the F.B.I.], 20 de marzo, 2002 [March 20, 2002]; 15.; 4 pages
    - Cuarto mensaje al F.B.I. [Fourth Message to the F.B.I.], 21 de marzo, 2002 [March 21, 2002]; 16.; 2 pages
    - Nota [Note], 1 de abril, 2002 [April 1, 2002]; 17.; 3 pages
    - Nota [Note], 4 de abril, 2002 [April 4, 2002]; 18.; 6 pages
    - Miscelánea [Miscellaneous], 11 de abril, 2002 [April 11, 2002]; 19.; 6 pages
    - Mensaje final dirigido a Cámara de los Comunes y M.1.6. en Londres: La civilización gravemente amenazada [Final Message Addressed to the House of Commons and M.1.6. in London: Civilization Seriously Threatened], 24 de abril, 2002 [April 24, 2002]; 20.; 4 pages
    - Reflexiones [Reflections], 29 de mayo, 2002 [May 29, 2002]; 21.; 6 pages
    - Un mensaje especial a la C.I.A. [A Special Message to the C.I.A.], 3 de junio, 2002 [June 3, 2002]; 22.; 4 pages
    - Reflexiones: La televisión [Reflections: Television], 4 de junio, 2002 [June 4, 2002]; 23.; 4 pages
    - Un mensaje especial a Defense Intelligence Agency [A Special Message to the Defense Intelligence Agency], 5 de junio, 2002 [June 5, 2002]; 24.; 4 pages
    - Reflexiones [Reflections], 15 de junio, 2002 [June 15, 2002]; 25.; 8 pages
    - Reflexiones [Reflections], 21 de junio, 2002 [June 21, 2002]; 26.; 6 pages
    - Reflexiones [Reflections], 25 de junio, 2002 [June 25, 2002]; 27.; 6 pages
    - Análisis: El ataque a las Torres Gemelas y al Pentágono [Analysis: The Attack on the Twin Towers and the Pentagon], 26 de junio, 2002 [June 26, 2002]; 28.; 3 pages
    - Reflexiones [Reflections], 27 de junio, 2002 [June 27, 2002]; 29.; 6 pages
    - Nota: Julio está pesimista, muy pesimista [Note: Julio is Pessimistic, Very Pessimistic], 28 de junio, 2002 [June 28, 2002]; 30.; 2 pages
    - Reflexiones [Reflections], 28 de junio, 2002 [June 28, 2002]; 31.; 3 pages
  - Writings, July-December 2002 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Nota [Note], 13 de julio, 2002 [July 13, 2002]; 1.; 1 page
    - Reflexiones especiales [Special Reflections], 1 de agosto, 2002 [August 1, 2002]; 2.; 7 pages
    - Un estudio político: La tragedia del Bajo Manhattan [Un estudio político: La tragedia del Bajo Manhattan], 9 de noviembre, 2002 [November 9, 2002]; 3.; 8 pages
    - Reflexiones [Reflections], 5 de diciembre, 2002 [December 5, 2002]; 4.; 6 pages
    - Análisis [Analysis], 8 de diciembre, 2002 [December 8, 2002]; 5.; 6 pages
    - Miscelánea [Miscellaneous], 10 de diciembre, 2002 [December 10, 2002]; 6.; 4 pages
    - Reflexiones [Reflections], 12 de diciembre, 2002 [December 12, 2002]; 7.; 3 pages
    - Análisis: Otro conflicto, en esta ocasión con Irán [Analysis: Another Conflict, This Time with Iran], 13 de diciembre, 2002 [December 13, 2002]; 8.; 5 pages
    - Reflexiones [Reflections], 18 de diciembre, 2002 [December 18, 2002]; 9.; 5 pages
  - Writings, March-May 2004 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Análisis [Analysis], 30 de marzo, 2003 [March 30, 2003]; 1.; 4 pages
    - Un breve mensaje [A Brief Message], 15 de junio, 2003 [June 15, 2003]; 2.; 2 pages
    - Cartas políticas: Israel, un estado terrorista. Para: Christopher Dodd, Tom Daschle, Sir Richard Billing Dearlove [Political Letters: Israel, A Terrorist State. To: Christopher Dodd, Tom Daschle, Sir Richard Billing Dearlove], 8 de marzo, 2004 [March 8, 2004]; 3.; 5 pages
    - Cartas políticas: Israel, un estado terrorista. Segunda parte [Political Letters: Israel, A Terrorist State. Second Part], 9 de marzo, 2004 [March 9, 2004]; 4.; 5 pages
    - Cartas políticas: Israel, un estado terrorista. Tercera parte [Political Letters: Israel, A Terrorist State. Third Part], 10 de marzo, 2004 [March 10, 2004]; 5.; 5 pages
    - Cartas políticas: Israel, un estado terrorista. Cuarta parte [Political Letters: Israel, A Terrorist State. Fourth Part], 11 de marzo, 2004 [March 11, 2004]; 6.; 6 pages
    - Cartas políticas: Israel, un estado terrorista. Quinta parte [Political Letters: Israel, A Terrorist State. Fifth Part], 12 de marzo, 2004 [March 12, 2004]; 7.; 5 pages
    - Cartas políticas: Israel, un estado terrorista. Sexta parte [Political Letters: Israel, A Terrorist State. Sixth Part], 13 de marzo, 2004 [March 13, 2004]; 8.; 6 pages
    - Cartas políticas: Israel, un estado terrorista. Séptima parte [Political Letters: Israel, A Terrorist State. Seventh Part], 14 de marzo, 2004 [March 14, 2004]; 9.; 5 pages
    - Cartas políticas: Israel, un estado terrorista. Octava parte [Political Letters: Israel, A Terrorist State. Eighth Part], 15 de marzo, 2004 [March 15, 2004]; 10.; 5 pages
    - Cartas políticas: Israel, un estado terrorista. Novena [Political Letters: Israel, A Terrorist State. Ninth Part], 16 de marzo, 2004 [March 16, 2004]; 11.; 7 pages
    - Cartas políticas: La tragedia de Iraq. Para: Christopher Dodd, Tom Daschle, Sir Richard Billing Dearlove. Primera parte [Political Letters: The Tragedy of Iraq. To: Christopher Dodd, Tom Daschle, Sir Richard Billing Dearlove. First part], 17 de marzo, 2004 [March 17, 2004]; 12.; 3 pages
    - Cartas políticas: La tragedia de Iraq. Segunda parte [Political Letters: The Tragedy of Iraq. Second Part], 18 de marzo, 2004 [March 18, 2004]; 13.; 4 pages
    - Cartas políticas: La tragedia de Iraq. Cuarta parte [Political Letters: The Tragedy of Iraq. Fourth Part], 20 de marzo, 2004 [March 20, 2004]; 14.; 7 pages
    - Cartas políticas: La tragedia de Iraq. Quinta parte [Political Letters: The Tragedy of Iraq. Fifth Part], 22 de marzo, 2004 [March 22, 2004]; 15.; 9 pages
    - Cartas políticas: La tragedia de Iraq. Parte final [Political Letters: The Tragedy of Iraq. Final Part], 23 de marzo, 2004 [March 23, 2004]; 16.; 9 pages
    - Crisis mundial: Un estudio político. Para: Gen. Wesley Clark. Primera parte [World Crisis: A Political Study.To: Gen. Wesley Clark. First Part], 31 de mayo, 2004 [May 31, 2004]; 17.; 2 pages
  - Writings, June-October 2004 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Crisis mundial: Un estudio político. Las relaciones Londres-Moscow son más profundas de lo que aparentan. Segunda parte [World Crisis: A Political Study. The London-Moscow Relations Are Deeper Than They Appear. Third Part], 3 de junio, 2004 [June 3, 2004]; 1.; 3 pages
    - Crisis mundial: Un estudio político. Comienza el avance hacia el 11 de septiembre. Tercera parte [World Crisis: A Political Study. The Advancement Towards September 11th Begins. Third Part], 4 de junio, 2004 [June 4, 2004]; 2.; 5 pages
    - Crisis mundial: Un estudio político. El avance hacia el 11 de septiembre. Quarta parte [World Crisis: A Political Study. The Advancement Towards September 11th. Fourth Part], 5 de junio, 2004 [June 5, 2004]; 3.; 6 pages
    - Crisis mundial: Un estudio político. Continúa el avance hacia el 11 de septiembre. Quinta parte [World Crisis: A Political Study. The Advancement Towards September 11th Continues, Fifth Part], 6 de junio, 2004 [June 6, 2004]; 4.; 5 pages
    - Crisis mundial: Un estudio político. Los sucesos del 11 de septiembre. Sexta parte [World Crisis: A Political Study. The Events of September 11th, Sixth Part], 6 de junio, 2004 [June 6, 2004]; 5.; 5 pages
    - Crisis mundial: Un estudio político. Séptima parte [World Crisis: A Political Study. Seventh Part], 7 de junio, 2004 [June 7, 2004]; 6.; 6 pages
    - Crisis mundial: Un estudio político. Octava parte [World Crisis: A Political Study. Eighth Part], 8 de junio, 2004 [June 8, 2004]; 7.; 6 pages
    - Crisis mundial: Un estudio político. Novena parte [World Crisis: A Political Study. Ninth Part], 9 de junio, 2004 [June 9, 2004]; 8.; 5 pages
    - Crisis mundial: Un estudio político. Novena parte, II [World Crisis: A Political Study. Ninth Part, II], 10 de junio, 2004 [June 10, 2004]; 9.; 7 pages
    - Nota [Note], 16 de junio, 2004 [June 16, 2004]; 10.; 5 pages
    - Nota [Note], 18 de junio, 2004 [June 18, 2004]; 11.; 4 pages
    - Nota [Note], 18 de junio, 2004 [June 18, 2004]; 12.; 1 page
    - Análisis: Es cierto que Al Qaeda atacará a los Estados Unidos? Qué se oculta detrás de ese anuncio? [Analysis: Is It True That Al Qaeda Attack the United States? What is Hiding Behind That Announcement?], 9 de julio, 2004 [July 9, 2004]; 13.; 7 pages
    - Un mensaje especial [A Special Message], 4 de agosto, 2004 [August 4, 2004]; 14.; 3 pages
    - Nota [Note], 5 de agosto, 2004 [August 5, 2004]; 15.; 1 page
    - Ideas para una solución [Ideas For a Solution], 9 de agosto, 2004 [August 9, 2004]; 16.; 3 pages
    - Nota [Note], 19 de agosto, 2004 [August 19, 2004]; 17.; 2 pages
    - Nota [Note], 20 de agosto, 2004 [August 20, 2004]; 18.; 3 pages
    - Nota [Note], 25 de agosto, 2004 [August 25, 2004]; 19.; 1 page
    - Nota [Note], 22 de septiembre, 2004 [September 22, 2004]; 20.; 2 pages
    - Nota [Note], 28 de septiembre, 2004 [September 28, 2004]; 21.; 2 pages
    - Un mensaje muy breve, pero enérgico [A Very Brief but Energetic Message], 5 de octubre, 2004 [October 5, 2004]; 22.; 3 pages
    - Un breve mensaje [A Brief Message], 8 de octubre, 2004 [October 8, 2004]; 23.; 1 page
  - Writings, 2005 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Nota [Note], 13 de enero, 2005 [January 13, 2005]; 1.; 1 page
    - Nota [Note], 19 de enero, 2005 [January 19, 2005]; 2.; 3 pages
    - Nota [Note], 21 de enero, 2005 [January 21, 2005]; 3.; 2 pages
    - Nota [Note], 24 de enero, 2005 [January 24, 2005]; 4.; 3 pages
    - Nota [Note], 26 de enero, 2005 [January 26, 2005]; 5.; 2 pages
    - Nota [Note], 28 de enero, 2005 [January 28, 2005]; 6.; 2 pages
    - Nota [Note], 2 de febrero, 2005 [February 2, 2005]; 7.; 1 page
    - Nota: Una semejanza que, cuidadosamente, deber ser observada [Note: A Similarity That, Carefully, Should Be Observed], 3 de febrero, 2005 [February 3, 2005]; 8.; 1 page
    - Análisis: La civilización americana ha estada fuertemente enlazada a una tiranía. Segunda parte [Analysis: The American Civilization Has Been Strongly Linked to a Tyranny. Second Part], 18 de marzo, 2005 [March 18, 2005]; 9.; 10 pages
    - Un mensaje a División Política del F.B.I. [A Message to the Political Division of the F.B.I.], 31 de marzo, 2005 [March 31, 2005]; 10.; 3 pages
    - Nota [Note], 14 de junio, 2005 [June 14, 2005]; 11.; 2 pages
    - Nota [Note], 15 de junio, 2005 [June 15, 2005]; 12.; 2 pages
    - Post Scriptum, 27 de junio, 2005 [June 27, 2005]; 13.; 2 pages
    - Nota muy importante [Very Important Note], 27 de junio, 2005 [June 27, 2005]; 14.; 1 page
    - Reflexiones: La drogadicción, cáncer que debe ser extirpado [Reflections: Drug Addiction, Cancer That Should Be Eradicated], 28 de junio, 2005 [June 28, 2005]; 15.; 3 pages
    - Nota: Se ganó la batalla contra el cáncer [Note: The Battle Against Cancer Has Been Won], 18 de octubre, 2005 [October 18, 2005]; 16.; 2 pages
  - Writings, 2007 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Momentos trascendentales. Tercera parte [Transcendental Moments. Third Part], 3 de abril, 2006 [April 3, 2006]; 1.; 4 pages
    - Mensajes trascendentales. Quarta parte [Transcendental Messages. Fourth Part], 9 de abril, 2006 [April 9, 2006]; 2.; 4 pages
    - Horas decisivas [Decisive Hours], 5 de junio, 2006 [June 5, 2006]; 3.; 3 pages
    - Nota [Note], 6 de junio, 2006 [June 6, 2006]; 4.; 1 page
    - Reflexiones [Reflections], 26 de febrero, 2007 [February 26, 2007]; 5.; 4 pages
    - Un momento decisivo [A Decisive Moment], 9 de marzo, 2007 [March 9, 2007]; 6.; 2 pages
    - Nota [Note], 9 de marzo, 2007 [March 9, 2007]; 7.; 1 page
    - Meditaciones [Contemplations], 9 de marzo, 2007 [March 9, 2007]; 8.; 3 pages
    - Nota [Note], 15 de marzo, 2007 [March 15, 2007]; 9.; 1 page
    - Meditaciones políticas [Political Contemplations], 19 de marzo, 2007 [March 19, 2007]; 10.; 6 pages
    - Un mensaje a la División Criminal del F.B.I. [A Message to the Criminal Division of the F.B.I.], 2 de abril, 2007 [April 2, 2007]; 11.; 3 pages
    - Segundo mensaje a la División Criminal [Second Message to the Criminal Division], 4 de abril, 2007 [April 4, 2007]; 12.; 3 pages
    - Una hora decisiva [A Decisive Hour], 10 de mayo, 2007 [May 10, 2007]; 13.; 2 pages
    - Nota [Note], 11 de mayo, 2007 [May 11, 2007]; 14.; 1 page
    - Julio comienza a movilizarse [Julio Begins to Mobilize], 12 de mayo, 2007 [May 12, 2007]; 15.; 2 pages
    - La batalla final de las ideas [The Final Battle of Ideas], 13 de mayo, 2007 [May 13, 2007]; 16.; 5 pages
    - Nota especial [Special Note], 16 de mayo, 2007 [May 16, 2007]; 17.; 2 pages
    - Los poderes de la evidencia [The Powers of Evidence], 21 de mayo, 2007 [May 21, 2007]; 18.; 3 pages
    - Un mensaje al Supremo Leadership, República Popular China y Alemania, la Alemania inmortal [A Message to the Supreme Leadership, the People's Republic of China and Germany, the Immortal Germany], 25 de agosto, 2007 [August 25, 2007]; 19.; 3 pages
    - Nota [Note], 26 de agosto, 2007 [August 26, 2007]; 20.; 1 page
- Writings, Undated, II.
  - Writings, Undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - La mente de Adolf Hitler [The Mind of Adolf Hitler], 1.; 4 pages
    - Cuba y la conjura en U.S.A. [Cuba and the Conspiracy in the U.S.A.], 2.; 3 pages
    - ¿Es Kissinger un agente de Moscú? Ford debe destituirlo de la Secretaría de Estado [Is Kissinger an Agent of Moscow? Ford Should Dismiss Him as Secretary of State], 3.; 3 pages
    - Llanto por U.S.A. [Weeping for the U.S.A.], 4.; 3 pages
    - Reflexiones de Primavera [Spring Reflections], 5.; 2 pages
    - África (La traición de Kissinger) [Africa (Kissinger's Betrayal)], 6.; 2 pages
    - Victoria de U.S.A. en el África del Norte (Triunfo de una teoría) [U.S.A.'s Victory in North Africa (Triumph of a Theory)], 7.; 2 pages
    - U.S.A.: Imperio universal [U.S.A.: Universal Empire], 8.; 2 pages
    - El viaje de Nixon a Moscú (Carta al exilio combatiente) [Nixon's Trip to Moscow (Letter to the Exiled Combatant)], 9.; 2 pages
    - Arafat en New York [Arafat in New York], 10.; 2 pages
    - Y Cuba, ¿cómo va la lucha? (Octava carta al exilio político) [And Cuba, How is the Fight Going? (Eighth Letter to the Exiled Politician)], 11.; 2 pages
    - El cine en la literatura [Film in Literature], 12.; 2 pages
    - El enemigo en la puerta [The Enemy at the Door], 13.; 3 pages
    - La reunión de Costa Rica (Décima quinta carta al Departamento de Estado) [The Reunion of Costa Rica (15th Letter to the Department of State)], 14.; 2 pages
    - La revolución cultural: Lin Piao [The Cultural Revolution: Lin Piao], 15.; 3 pages
    - Elogio de Joe Louis [Praise for Joe Louis], 16.; 3 pages
    - En la tierra de Agramonte [In the Land of Agramonte], 17.; 3 pages
    - La crisis hemisférica (Un análisis político) [Hemispheric Crisis (A Political Analysis)], 18.; 2 pages
    - Las relaciones con Pekín (Octavo mensaje al National Security Council) [Relations with Beijing (Eighth Message to the National Security Council)], 19.; 2 pages
    - Los cubanos deben de votar por Ford (Especial para Guerra) [Cubans Should Vote for Ford (Special for Guerra)], 20.; 2 pages
    - El Ángel de la derrota (Décima octava carta el Pentágono) [The Angel of Defeat (18th Letter to the Pentagon)], 21.; 2 pages
    - ¿Qué se oculta tras el ataque a la C.I.A.? (La conjura es contra U.S.A.) [What Hides Behind the Attack on the C.I.A.? (The Conspiracy is Against the U.S.A.)], 22.; 2 pages
    - Las relaciones con China (Especial para Guerra) [Relations with China (Special for Guerra)], 23.; 2 pages
    - El imperio (Washington como centro del mundo) [The Empire (Washington as the Center of the World)], 24.; 2 pages
    - El presidente en Europa [The President in Europe], 25.; 2 pages
    - Dios salve a U.S.A. (Carta sin sobre al pentágono) [God Save the U.S.A. (Letter Without Envelope to the Pentagon)], 26.; 3 pages
    - La revolución cultural: La tormenta [The Cultural Revolution: The Storm], 27.; 3 pages
    - Otro año trágico [Another Tragic Year], 28.; 2 pages
  - Writings, Undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Ha hablado Nixon (Septuagésima primera carta el Pentágono) [Nixon Has Spoken (71st Letter to the Pentagon)], 1.; 3 pages
    - Kissinger, 2.; 3 pages
    - Estado palestino (Especial para Guerra) [Palestinian State (Special for Guerra)], 3.; 2 pages
    - Moscu humilla a Washington (Quadragésima segunda carta al Departamento de Estado) [Moscow Humiliates Washington (42nd Letter to the Department of State)], 4.; 2 pages
    - El futuro de U.S.A.: Reflexiones politicas de mayo (Décimo mensaje al National Security Council) [The Future of the U.S.A.: Political Reflections of May (Tenth Message to the National Security Council)], 5.; 3 pages
    - Subversión permanente (Trigésima quinta carta al Departamento de Estado) [Permanent Subversion (35th Letter to the Department of State)], 6.; 2 pages
    - La OTAN en peligro (Cuadragésima sexta carta al Pentágono) [OTAN in Danger (46th Letter to the Pentagon)], 7.; 2 pages
    - El congreso está reaccionando (Décimo sexto mensaje al National Security Council) [Congress is Reacting (16th Message to the National Security Council)], 8.; 2 pages
    - Meditación del caudillo (Tercero de una serie) [Reflection of the Leadership (Third of a Series)], 9.; 3 pages
    - Kissinger a la America Latina (Especial para Avance) [Kissinger to Latin America (Special for Avance)], 10.; 2 pages
    - Opio subversivo (Especial para Avance) [Subversive Opium (Special for Advance)], 11.; 2 pages
    - Es imperativa una dirigencia [A Leadership is Imperative], 12.; 2 pages
    - Crisis en U.S.A. [Crisis in the U.S.A.], 13.; 3 pages
    - Arte, deporte y política [Art, Sports, and Politics], 14.; 3 pages
    - La crisis hemisférica [The Hemispheric Crisis], 15.; 2 pages
    - Panorama de la lucha (Cuarta carta el exilio político cubano) [Panorama of the Fight (Fourth Letter to the Exiled Cuban Politician)], 16.; 3 pages
    - ¿Cuál es la situación? (Quinta carta al exilio político cubano) [What is the Situation? (Fifth Letter to the Exiled Cuban Politician)], 17.; 3 pages
    - La mano soviética [The Soviet Hand], 18.; 2 pages
    - Examen y conclusiones [Examination and Conclusions], 19.; 2 pages
    - Tensión mundial a la vista [World Tension in Sight], 20.; 2 pages
    - Los zarpazos del dinosaurio [The Lashings of the Dinosaur], 21.; 3 pages
    - La casa blanca está ciega (Sexta carta sin sobre al Pentágono) [The White House is Blind (Sixth Letter Without an Envelope to the Pentagon)], 22.; 2 pages
    - El Pentágono y el idealismo [The Pentagon and Idealism], 23.; 3 pages
    - Evocación de México [Evocation of Mexico], 24.; 3 pages
    - La conjura está derrotada [The Conspiracy is Defeated], 25.; 4 pages
    - La mente de Adolf Hitler (Tercera parte) [The Mind of Adolf Hitler (Third Part)], 26.; 4 pages
    - El cáncer del hemisferio [The Cancer of the Hemisphere], 27.; 3 pages
    - Cambodia debe ser salvada [Cambodia Should Be Saved], 28.; 2 pages
    - Moscú y Tel Aviv se besan (Quincuagésima novena carta al Pentágono) [Moscow and Tel Aviv Kiss (59th Letter to the Pentagon)], 29.; 2 pages
    - U.S.A.: Confrontación a la vista [U.S.A.: Confrontation in Sight], 30.; 4 pages
    - Sangre, terror y azúcar (Séptima carta al Pentágono) [Blood, Terror, and Sugar (Seventh Letter to the Pentagon)], 31.; 2 pages
  - Writings, Undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Alumbrando el camino [Illuminating the Way], 1.; 2 pages
    - Nubarrones sobre China [Storm Clouds over China], 2.; 3 pages
    - Palabras cordiales a una dama [Cordial Words to a Lady], 3.; 3 pages
    - Alemania está correcta [Germany is Correct], 4.; 2 pages
    - La mano de Kissinger (Cuadragésima novena carta al Pentágono) [The Hand of Kissinger (49th Letter to the Pentagon)], 5.; 2 pages
    - Reina una época nueva (Ideas para reconstruir Cuba) [A New Era Reigns (Ideas to Reconstruct Cuba)], 6.; 2 pages
    - Kissinger es un traidor (Octava carta al Pentagono) [Kissinger is a Traitor (Eight Letter to the Pentagon)], 7.; 2 pages
    - El espiritu del 33 [The Spirit of 33], 8.; 2 pages
    - Mito y subversión [Myth and Subversion], 9.; 3 pages
    - Humilde homenaje [Humble Tribute], 10.; 3 pages
    - Abrazo arabe-norteamericano [Arab-North American Embrace], 11.; 2 pages
    - U.S.A.: Negros nubarrones [U.S.A.: Black Storm Clouds], 12.; 3 pages
    - Cuba y el horizonte [Cuba and the Horizon], 13.; 2 pages
    - Washington-Pekin: La alianza de oro [Washington-Beijing: Alliance of Gold], 14.; 3 pages
    - Propaganda y totalitarismo [Propaganda and Totalitarianism], 15.; 3 pages
    - Jorge Bolet: Su momento cumbre [Jorge Bolet: His highest moment], 16.; 3 pages
    - Castrismo e intelectualidad [Castroism and Intellectuality], 17.; 3 pages
    - Puñales en la sombra [Daggers in the Shade], 18.; 2 pages
    - Pinceladas [Strokes], 19.; 2 pages
    - La república [The Republic], 20.; 2 pages
    - ¿Cuál es la situación? [What is the Situation?], 21.; 3 pages
    - La ciudad [The City], 22.; 3 pages
    - La bomba atómica [The Atomic Bomb], 23.; 3 pages
    - Fracaso de una teoría [Failure of a Theory], 24.; 3 pages
    - Guerra en el bajo mundo [War in the Underworld], 25.; 3 pages
    - Kissinger debe ser destituído [Kissinger Should Be Dismissed], 26.; 2 pages
    - Orientando a los desterrados [Guiding the Outcasts], 27.; 4 pages
    - Subversión social en el hemisferio (Cuarta carta al Pentágono) [Social Subversion in the Hemisphere (Fourth Letter to the Pentagon)], 28.; 3 pages
    - China: Veinte y cinco años después [China: 25 Years Later], 29.; 3 pages
    - Fuerza e inteligencia [Strength and Intelligence], 30.; 3 pages
    - Fracaso de una teoría [Failure of a Theory], 31.; 3 pages
  - Writings, Undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - El calvario de Cuba (Carta sin sobre al Departamento de Estado) [The Calvary of Cuba (Letter Without Envelope to the Department of State)], 1.; 4 pages
    - Evocación de Edith Piaf [Evocation of Edith Piaf], 2.; 3 pages
    - Palabras al exilio [Words to the Exile], 3.; 3 pages
    - El Pentágono: Su misión de gloria [The Pentagon: Its Mission of Glory], 4.; 3 pages
    - La reconstrucción nacional [National Reconstruction], 5.; 3 pages
    - Washington a la defensiva (Septuagésima quinta carta al Pentágono) [Washington on the Defensive (75th Letter to the Pentagon)], 6.; 2 pages
    - La tiranía soviética (Un estudio político) [The Soviet Tyranny (A Political Study)], 7.; 2 pages
    - La mente de Adolf Hitler (Tercero de una serie) [The Mind of Adolf Hitler (Third of a Series)], 8.; 3 pages
    - Kissinger y su nueva política para África [Kissinger and His New Policy for Africa], 9.; 3 pages
    - Nace una industria [An Industry is Born], 10.; 2 pages
    - Estrategia de Victoria [Strategy of Victory], 11.; 2 pages
    - Realidad y fantasía [Reality and Fantasy], 12.; 2 pages
    - La caída de Makarios (Epílogo de un drama apasionante) [The Fall of Makarios (Epilogue of a Passionate Drama)], 13.; 4 pages